Speaker 1: India is a nation marked by an incredible linguistic diversity and an inclusive vision.
Speaker 1: This ancient land is transforming itself into a Viksit Bharat,
Speaker 1: with knowledge and technology as key enablers.
Speaker 1: Contributing towards this mission is Vikas Pedia, a technology initiative
Speaker 1: that harnesses collective wisdom to promote multilingual open knowledge repositories
Speaker 1: for an inclusive cyber space.
Speaker 1: Vikas Pedia is an initiative of the Ministry of Electronics and IT, Government of India,
Speaker 1: and executed by Centre for Development of Advanced Computing.
Speaker 1: It fosters an AI augmented multi-stakeholder digital ecosystem.
Speaker 1: This robust and user-centric ecosystem is powered by technology,
Speaker 1: capacities, knowledge and sustainability enablers.
Speaker 1: The heart of the initiative is Vikas Pedia's AI enabled multilingual,
Speaker 1: multimodal and multisectoral collaborative knowledge sharing framework.
Speaker 1: The framework supports a suite of AI tools to augment content authoring,
Speaker 1: digitization, translation, review, discovery and delivery of digital resources
Speaker 1: in 22 constitutionally recognized languages of the country.
Speaker 1: It is designed to harness the collective wisdom of the linguistically
Speaker 1: and culturally diverse Bharat.
Speaker 1: The framework caters to a one-stop platform, hosting diverse information
Speaker 1: on multiple sectors and is developed using microservices based architecture.
Speaker 1: It follows a mobile first approach, supporting multiple media formats
Speaker 1: and has rich user engagement features including accessibility tools.
Speaker 1: Let's connect, collaborate, communicate and co-create for a Viksit Bharat.
Speaker 1: We are thankful to the Ministry of Electronics and IT for supporting this initiative.