India is a nation marked by an incredible linguistic diversity and inclusive vision.
This ancient land is transforming itself into a Vixit Bharat with knowledge and technology as key enablers.
Contributing towards this mission is Vikaspedia, a technology initiative that harnesses collective wisdom
to promote multilingual open knowledge repositories for an inclusive cyberspace.
Vikaspedia is an initiative of the Ministry of Electronics and IT, Government of India
and executed by Centre for Development of Advanced Computing.
It fosters an AI-augmented multi-stakeholder digital ecosystem.
This robust and user-centric ecosystem is powered by technology, capacities, knowledge and sustainability enablers.
The heart of the initiative is Vikaspedia's AI-enabled Multilingual, Multimodal and Multisectoral Collaborative Knowledge-Sharing Framework.
The framework supports a suite of AI tools to augment content authoring, digitization, translation, review, discovery and delivery of digital resources in 20 to constitutionally recognized languages of the country.
It is designed to harness the collective wisdom of the community.
It is designed to harness the collective wisdom of the linguistically and culturally diverse Bharat.
The framework caters to a one-stop platform, hosting diverse information on multiple sectors and is developed using microservices-based architecture.
It follows a mobile-first approach, supporting multiple media formats and has rich user engagement features, including accessibility tools.
Let's connect, collaborate, communicate and share.
Let's communicate and co-create for a Vixit Bharat.
We are thankful to the Ministry of Electronics and IT for supporting this initiative.